A Guide to the Ketoctin Chapter, DAR Genealogical Records Committee Reports, 2001-
Thomas Balch Library
Thomas Balch Library
Ketoctin Chapter, DAR Genealogical Records Committee Reports 2001-
Thomas Balch Library
M 051
The Ketoctin Chapter, DAR Genealogical Records Committee Reports collection contains duplicate copies of reports submitted by the Ketoctin Chapter to the NSDAR as pertaining to Virginia, especially Loudoun County.
Ketoctin Chapter, DAR
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection open for research.
Acquisition Information
Multiple sources
Alternative Form Available
None
Accruals
2004.0072, 2006.0003, 2010.0286
Historical Information
The National Society Daughters of the American Revolution (NSDAR or just DAR) is a non-profit, non-political volunteer women's service organization founded in 1890 and headquartered in Washington, D.C. The Ketoctin Chapter was organized in Bluemont, Loudoun County, in 1950. At both the local and national level, the DAR encourages patriotism, preservation of American history, and educational projects.
In 1913, the DAR Genealogical Research Committee (GRC) was formed with the primary purpose of collecting and indexing unpublished genealogical records. In 1932, the committee changed its name to the Genealogical Records Committee, and in 1986 became a project under the directorship of the Librarian General. Local and state chapters submit projects to the national organization for inclusion in the project.
Scope and Content
The Ketoctin Chapter, DAR Genealogical Records Committee Reports collection contains duplicate copies of reports submitted by the Ketoctin Chapter to the NSDAR as pertaining to Virginia, especially Loudoun County. Individual reports include copies and transcriptions of Bible records, abstracts of official records, and cemetery readings. Thomas Balch Library staff and volunteers prepared a supplementary index, located in folder 1, to some of the materials.
All materials donated by local and state chapters to the NSDAR under the auspices of the GRC project, including the items in this collection, are catalogued and bound by the national DAR. The bound volumes were converted to an electronic database available to researchers at the DAR Library in Washington, D.C; an index is available at http://services.dar.org/Public/DAR_Research/search/?Tab_ID=6.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Bibliography
Daughters of the American Revolution: About DAR, http://www.dar.org/natsociety/whoweare.cfm, accessed 4 October 2010
DAR Records (M 051), Thomas Balch Library, Leesburg, VA.
Ketoctin Chapter, National Society, Daughters of the American Revolution, http://www.ketoctinchapterdar.org/, accessed 6 October 2010
Personal communication, Elizabeth Hopkins, Genealogical Records Committee (GRC) Office, NSDAR, 4 October 2010
Location of Originals
NSDAR, Washington, D.C.
Other Finding Aid
DAR Records Index (paper and electronic)
Technical Requirements
None
Related Material
Family Bible Records (M 050), Family Files; DAR Patriot Index (3 editions: V REF 929.3 DAU, V REF 929.373 DAU; V REF 929.1 DAU); A Half Century of Patriotism: The History of the Ketoctin Chapter-The National Society of the Daughters of the American Revolution, 1950-2000 by Carol A. Kupchik and Florence M. Hillman (V REF 975.528 KUP); Forgotten Patriots: African American and American Indian Patriots in the Revolutionary War: A Guide to Service, Sources And Studies, Eric Grundset, ed (V REF 973.34 GRU)
Contents List
- Index to folders 2-4 n.d. (Folder 1)
- Series 2, Volume 79: Virginia DAR Genealogical Committee Report: Accomack and Northampton Counties2001 (Folder 2)
- Series 2, Volume 80: Virginia DAR Genealogical Committee Report: Mortuary Records January 1883-April 1895 and Green Hill Cemetery Updaten.d. (Folder 3)
- Series 2, Volume 81: Virginia DAR Genealogical Committee Report: Miscellaneous Virginia Records2002 (Folder 4)
- Genealogical Records of Governor Westmoreland Delaware Davis 2005 (Folder 5)
- Bible of M.D. Wallis 2005 (Folder 6)
- Articles of Agreement, Chester County PA 1785 2005 (Folder 7)
- Articles of Agreement - Evan Phillips & Davis Thomas 2005 (Folder 8)
- Chestnut Grove Cemetery, Herndon - Inventoryca. 1976 (Folder 9)
- Wills of Best, Davis, Hague, McGeach, Loudoun County, Virginia, 1767-1770 2008 (Folder 10)
- Wills of Adams, Booth, Jenney, McGeach, Roberts, Sinckler, Spurr, Yates, Loudoun County, Virginia, 1758-1761 2009 (Folder 11)